Strength Now. Courage Always. Family, Above All. Batman and Robin!
Batman & Robin is a action, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Joel Schumacher.
Batman and his sidekick Robin attempt to the foil the sinister schemes of a
deranged set of new villains, most notably the melancholy Mr.
Freeze, who wants to make Gotham City into an arctic region, and
the sultry Poison Ivy, a botanical femme fatale.
As the Dynamic Duo contend with these bad guys, a third hero,
Batgirl, joins the ranks of the city's crime-fighters.
Bruce Wayne / Batman, played by George Clooney.
Dick Grayson / Robin, played by Chris O'Donnell.
Dr. Victor Fries / Mr. Freeze, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Dr. Pamela Isley / Poison Ivy, played by Uma Thurman.
Barbara Wilson / Batgirl, played by Alicia Silverstone.
Alfred Pennyworth, played by Michael Gough.
Batman & Robin is a 1997 American superhero film based on the DC Comics
characters Batman and Robin by Bill Finger and Bob Kane.
It is the fourth and final installment of Warner Bros.' initial Batman film
series (1989–1997) and a sequel to Batman Forever (1995).
Directed by Joel Schumacher and written by Akiva Goldsman, it stars George Clooney as Bruce Wayne / Batman and Chris
O'Donnell as Dick Grayson / Robin, alongside Arnold Schwarzenegger, Uma Thurman, and Alicia Silverstone.
The film follows the titular characters as they oppose Mr.
Freeze and Poison Ivy, while struggling to keep their partnership together.
Warner Bros.
fast-tracked development for Batman & Robin following the box office success of Batman Forever;
Schumacher was given a mandate to make the film more toyetic than its predecessor.
Schumacher and Goldsman conceived the storyline
during pre-production on A Time to Kill.
After Val Kilmer decided not to reprise the role of Batman, Schumacher was
interested in casting William Baldwin before Clooney won the role.
Principal photography began in September 1996 and wrapped in
January 1997, two weeks ahead of the shooting schedule.
Batman & Robin is the only film in the initial Batman film series made
without the involvement of Tim Burton in any capacity.
Batman & Robin premiered in Los Angeles on June 12, 1997,
and went into general release on June 20.
It grossed $238 million worldwide against a production budget of $125–160
million, and was considered a box office disappointment at the time.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and is
considered to be one of the worst films ever made.
The film's poor reception caused Warner Bros.
to cancel future Batman films, including Schumacher's planned Batman Unchained.
One of the songs recorded for the film, "The End Is the Beginning Is the End" by the Smashing
Pumpkins, won a Grammy Award for Best Hard Rock Performance at the 40th Annual Grammy Awards.
The film explores themes of dual identity, double
life, crime fighter, superhero, ice age.
The tone is thought_provoking.